<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: arcade | Marcus Young]]></title>
  <link href="https://marcyoung.us/blog/categories/arcade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://marcyoung.us/"/>
  <updated>2022-02-16T01:35:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://marcyoung.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marcus Young]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Arcade rebuilds]]></title>
    <link href="https://marcyoung.us/post/arcade_rebuilds"/>
    <updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://marcyoung.us/post/arcades</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent a good chunk of 2021 rebuilding arcades for people <!-- more --></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
If you&rsquo;re going to send me hate letters for pandoras box: go ahead and hit the back button. I made these for people who dont want a bunch of arcades, so every single one of these was pandoras box.
<br/>
<br/>
I&rsquo;ll share some before and afters:</p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
<br/>
An atari centipede (already JAMMA) in mostly good condition. <br/>
* Turned into Pandoras box<br/>
* The CRT was bad, they wanted it LCD<br/>
* They wanted to just turn the marquee blank<br/>
* The 6 button wiring harness was a joke<br/>
* I wanted to keep the steel control board so I welded back all the button holes and redrilled and added some nice polylaminate artwork over it<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/Centipede.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
A knock off galaga<br/>
* Turned into Pandoras box<br/>
* The control panel was hacked together on &frac34;&#8221; MDF<br/>
* A real fire hazard internally<br/>
* CRT was bad, but the glass was good. The &ldquo;marquee&rdquo; was just paint on the backside: easily removed with acetone<br/>
* Wood was mostly saveable minus the water soaked edges/corners. Fixed with lots of sanding and bondo.<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/galaga.jpg"><br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/galaga1.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
A Stern Berzerk in absolute terrible condition<br/>
* Turned into Pandoras box<br/>
* This took 90% of the time just to sand.<br/>
* All the wood is pressed wood that had started to come apart at the bottom. Had to cut it all off and fix with bondo<br/>
* Custom cut a new control panel from &frac34;&#8221; MDF<br/>
* The CRT was bad, replaced with a monitor inlaid into a new &frac34;&#8221; MDF with a router for the bezel cover<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/stern.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
Knock off WWE Wrestlefest turned Survival Arts<br/>
* Rewired to CHAMMA, added pandoras box<br/>
* CRT was still in great shape, no glass and didnt have the ability to cut plexi. Sold at a yard sale<br/>
* CPO was hacked together with plexi over it. Cut all new &frac34;&#8221; for the 6 buttons, kept the hardware + plexi<br/>
* Repainted, 3d printed a &ldquo;MAME&rdquo; marquee and glued to a new marquee<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/survival_arts.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
Zaxxon hacked into a poker game<br/>
* Disgusting estate sale find. <br/>
* Contained dead rat<br/>
* CRT was saveable with some magnet work<br/>
* Recut new CPO from &frac34;&#8221; MDF and wired to CHAMMA with pandoras box<br/>
* Kept all artwork and 90s style fake wood laminate<br/>
* 3d printed a cover for the front hole (not pictured)<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/zaxxon.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
Completely empty MK2 shell<br/>
* Stole CPO from another similar Midway shell<br/>
* Customer wanted light up LEDs which required hacking up all the button PCBs to separate the ground and voltage and wiring them to the +5V on the CHAMMA harness<br/>
* New LCD built into shell from a 32&#8221; TV<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/mk2.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
Gem fighter<br/>
* A dynamo cabinet turned into gem fighter<br/>
* They wanted mrs pacman marquee and a generic multi-game CPO - a nice polylaminate one with zelda, donkey kong, pacman etc<br/>
* Wood was originally in great shape, CRT was bad. Said fixable but needed a complete overhaul. Used an LCD to replace.<br/>
* Paint touch up, replacement locks<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/gem_fighter.jpg"></p>

<p><br/>
<br/>
Custom 4 Player from MK1 cabinet<br/>
* MK1 cabinet modified to fit a 4 player CPO<br/>
* Built dimensions to fit, using custom latching system to remove (does not fit through a standard door as-is)<br/>
* 2 Players are to CHAMMA harness as usual, the other 2 players are USB into pandoras box. Worked surprisingly easy<br/>
* Wanted it galaga themed, so galaga marquee and side artwork ordered to fit<br/>
* Original 25&#8221; CRT still worked great, added plexi<br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/mk1_1.jpg"><br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/mk1_2.jpg"><br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/mk1_3.jpg"><br/>
<img src="/images/arcade/mk1_4.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcaderator - Building An Arcade Kegerator]]></title>
    <link href="https://marcyoung.us/post/barcade"/>
    <updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://marcyoung.us/post/Barcaderator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Introducing a modular arcade kegerator  <!-- more --></p>

<h3>The Backstory</h3>

<p>I recenly got into doing random stuff with arcades.
In October 2018 I got ahold of a completely ripped apart San Fransisco Rush cabinet.
I redid some of the wood, built a computer into it, reversed all the controls into a teensy and made it play Rocket League.
My tattoo shop is currently painting it (build log to come when I have it back).</p>

<p>In trade, I&rsquo;m fixing their arcade machine.</p>

<p>So now apparently I like real arcade machines <a href="https://marcyoung.us/post/mame-cabinet/">and not my now-broken table top</a>.</p>

<p>I also brew beer. Why not combine the two?!</p>

<p>So I introduce to you:</p>

<p><img src="/images/barcade1.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade2.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade3.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade2.gif">
<img src="/images/marquee.gif"></p>

<h3>The Hardware</h3>

<ul>
<li>The Marquee is a custom &ldquo;vintage style neon light&rdquo; from a company on alibaba.</li>
<li>The Computer is a <a href="https://www.dfrobot.com/product-1727.html?search=lattepanda%20alpha&amp;description=true">lattepanda alpha</a></li>
<li>The LED Buttons are <a href="https://groovygamegear.com/webstore/index.php?main_page=product_info&amp;products_id=408">spectra eclipse</a></li>
<li>The LED controller is an <a href="https://www.arcaderenovations.com/ultimarc-pacled64.html">Ultimarc pacled64</a></li>
<li>The Cabinet was custom cut on a CNC</li>
<li>The &ldquo;split&rdquo; frame is based on <a href="https://cdn11.bigcommerce.com/s-ecrovlce13/images/stencil/500x659/products/10801/13177/pygcjgwqewky6od7qomr__54105.1563214651.png?c=2">this style of aluminum tongue/receiver</a> from TCH hardware</li>
<li>The &ldquo;latches&rdquo; and the handles for the split top are from TCH Hardware</li>
</ul>


<h3>The Software</h3>

<p>The lattepanda runs Ubuntu with MAME. I originally chose windows, but LEDBlinky is <em>awful</em>. Just awful.
So instead I&rsquo;ve been working with <a href="https://sourceforge.net/p/ledspicer/wiki/Home/">LEDSpicer by Patricio Rossi</a>. The software worked nearly out of the box and he&rsquo;s been super helpful for getting me up and running.</p>

<h3>Build Pics</h3>

<p><img src="/images/barcade/build2.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build3.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build4.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build5.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build6.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build7.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build8.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build9.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build10.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build11.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build12.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build13.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build14.jpg">
<img src="/images/barcade/build15.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
