<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ergoslider | Marcus Young]]></title>
  <link href="https://marcyoung.us/blog/categories/ergoslider/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://marcyoung.us/"/>
  <updated>2022-01-28T23:01:50+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://marcyoung.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marcus Young]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ergoslider Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://marcyoung.us/post/ergoslider-review"/>
    <updated>2017-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://marcyoung.us/post/ergoslider-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another ergonomic mouse review I gone and did <!-- more --></p>

<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been on an ergo kick (no pain, just realized how much more efficient I am).</p>

<p>I reached out to a company selling a product much like the ContourMouse ergo mice but at a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ergoslider-Plus-Ergonomic-Roller-Bar-Tendinitis/dp/B071JNSD9Z/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1507601165&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=ergoslider">much lower price</a>.</p>

<p>My assumption was that it would be ergo&#8217;ish but clunky. I was wrong. This thing is great!</p>

<p>The first thing I realized, and drove me crazy for a few minutes, is that the roller bar is not attached. The documents don&rsquo;t say much, so I first thought I was missing a part. It says it&rsquo;s detached, but it didnt make sense to my brain. So after finding nothing in the booklet I just dropped it in its place and it was working. Strange. The contourmouse ones have it on a metal bar, this doenst pretend that. If you&rsquo;ve cleaned a contourmouse bar, its pretty awful. Requires bending metal, etc. This thing is cool, just remove it and rub it down with an alcohol wipe, done. I did wish it locked into place somehow though, because the drive to work involved it getting wedged under something in my backpack.</p>

<p>In terms of usage, this thing is very much what I expected, plus some. Its very fluid, feels solid, and works great. The OS (mac + windows) worked immediately with it and didn&rsquo;t require pulling any software/drivers down.</p>

<p>After using it for about 30 days now, I can say that if you&rsquo;re looking for an ergo mouse at a small price, look no further. This has been my go-to and will likely stay that way. It&rsquo;s been at our &ldquo;standing desk&rdquo; area for about two weeks and has prompted quite a few questions and quite a bit of usage.</p>

<p>My only cons:</p>

<ol>
<li>The detachable mouse is both a pro and a con. It&rsquo;s great because it&rsquo;s detachable, but it&rsquo;s not because it&rsquo;s detached. It&rsquo;s not actually detachable, because it&rsquo;s literally always loose. Can probably get lost easily.</li>
<li>The drivers are non-customizable. You can&rsquo;t map the buttons  to anything else, they are what they say they are. The biggest plus to contour mouse is that the keys are 100% mappable through software.</li>
</ol>


<p>The pros:</p>

<ol>
<li>Pretty much anything you can imagine about an ergo mouse: comfort, quality, usage, ease.</li>
</ol>


<p>Overall: buy this if you want to save a bit of cash.</p>

<p>Pics below</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/ergoslider1.jpg">
<img class="left" src="/images/ergoslider2.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
